{
    "multipleChoice": {
        "easy": [
            {
                "question": "When was the Tran Dynasty established? ",
                "options": [
                    "Early 1226",
                    "1228",
                    "1225",
                    "1863"
                ],
                "answer": "Early 1226"
            },
            {
                "question": "How many kings did the Nguyen Dynasty have? ",
                "options": [
                    "2",
                    "13",
                    "5",
                    "6"
                ],
                "answer": "13"
            },
            {
                "question": "In what year and from where did Nguyen Tat Thanh set out to find a way to save the country? ",
                "options": [
                    "1911, at Nha Rong port",
                    "1912, at Saigon Station",
                    "1913, at Mr Le's house",
                    "1915, at Nha Rong post"
                ],
                "answer": "1911, at Nha Rong port"
            },
            {
                "question": "How many phases were there in the Dien Bien Phu campaign?",
                "options": [
                    "2 phases",
                    "3 phases",
                    "4 phases",
                    "1 phases"
                ],
                "answer": "3 phases"
            },
            {
                "question": "How many days and nights did Vietnam win the Dien Bien Phu campaign?",
                "options": [
                    "55 days and nights",
                    "56 days and night",
                    "65 days and night",
                    "50 days and nights"
                ],
                "answer": "56 days and nights"
            },
            {
                "question": "What is Vietnam's national day?",
                "options": [
                    "2/9",
                    "12/9",
                    "19/8",
                    "3/9"
                ],
                "answer": "2/9"
            },
            {
                "question": "What day, month, and year did General Secretary Nguyen Phu Trong pass away?",
                "options": [
                    "July 19, 2024",
                    "July 20, 2024",
                    "May 19, 2024",
                    "June 19, 2024"
                ],
                "answer": "July 19, 2024"
            },
            {
                "question": "What day is national reunification day?",
                "options": [
                    "30/4/1975",
                    "30/4/1974",
                    "30/3/1975",
                    "29/4/1975"
                ],
                "answer": "30/4/1975"
            },
            {
                "question": "Who was the commander of the Dien Bien Phu campaign?",
                "options": [
                    "Uncle Ho",
                    "General Vo Nguyen Giap",
                    "General Le Trong Tan",
                    "Hoang Van Thai"
                ],
                "answer": "General Vo Nguyen Giap"
            },
            {
                "question": "During the years 1955-1975, which country provided economic and technical to Vietnam?",
                "options": [
                    "England",
                    "France",
                    "Soviet Union",
                    "Thailand"
                ],
                "answer": "Soviet Union"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which dynasty was founded by Nguyen Anh after defeating Tay Son?",
                "options": [
                    "Le Dynasty",
                    "Nguyen Dynasty",
                    "Tran Dynasty",
                    "Han Dynasty"
                ],
                "answer": "Nguyen Dynasty"
            },
            {
                "question": "How long was Vietnam colonized by China?",
                "options": [
                    "900 years",
                    "Over 1000 years",
                    "800 years",
                    "Over 700 years"
                ],
                "answer": "Over 1000 years"
            },
            {
                "question": "What year did World War II end?",
                "options": [
                    "1945",
                    "1946",
                    "1944",
                    "1943"
                ],
                "answer": "1945"
            },
            {
                "question": "Who was the US President when the Paris Peace Agreement was signed?",
                "options": [
                    "John F. Kennedy",
                    "Lyndon B. Johnson",
                    "Gerald Ford",
                    "Richard Nixon"
                ],
                "answer": "Richard Nixon"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which country did the US drop atomic bombs on during World War II? ",
                "options": [
                    "VietNam",
                    "China",
                    "Japan",
                    "Laos"
                ],
                "answer": "Japan"
            },
            {
                "question": "The first country in the world to build a nuclear power plant was",
                "options": [
                    "America",
                    "China",
                    "Japan",
                    "Soviet Union"
                ],
                "answer": "Soviet Union"
            },
            {
                "question": "Where is the headquarters of the United Nations located?",
                "options": [
                    "VietNam",
                    "America",
                    "China",
                    "Singapore"
                ],
                "answer": "America"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which country initiated the conquest of space?",
                "options": [
                    "Soviet Union",
                    "America",
                    "Japan",
                    "Singapore"
                ],
                "answer": "Soviet Union"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which energy source is considered 'clean energy'?",
                "options": [
                    "Thermonuclear energy",
                    "Solar energy",
                    "Tidal energy",
                    "Nuclear energy"
                ],
                "answer": "Solar energy"
            },
            {
                "question": "In which country was the first electronic computer invented?",
                "options": [
                    "America",
                    "Soviet Union",
                    "Japan",
                    "France"
                ],
                "answer": "America"
            }
        ],
        "normal": [
            {
                "question": "Who was the president of the United States during World War I?",
                "options": [
                    "Woodrow Wilson",
                    "Theodore Roosevelt",
                    "Franklin D. Roosevelt",
                    "Warren G. Harding"
                ],
                "answer": "Woodrow Wilson"
            },
            {
                "question": "What was the first name of our country? ",
                "options": [
                    "Van Lang",
                    "Au Lac",
                    "VietNam",
                    "Dai Co Viet"
                ],
                "answer": "Van Lang"
            },
            {
                "question": "What day, month, and year was Nguyen Tat Thanh born?",
                "options": [
                    "May 19, 1980",
                    "May 19, 1890",
                    "May 19, 1089",
                    "May 19, 1908"
                ],
                "answer": "May 19, 1890"
            },
            {
                "question": "When did the Ho Chi Minh Campaign take place? ",
                "options": [
                    "From April 16 to April 30, 1975 ",
                    "From April 26 to April 30, 1975",
                    "From April 9 to April 30, 1975",
                    "From April 21 to April 30, 1975"
                ],
                "answer": "From April 26 to April 30, 1975"
            },
            {
                "question": "What date was the Paris Agreement signed? ",
                "options": [
                    "27/01/1973",
                    "28/01/1975",
                    "2/9/1954",
                    "30/4/1975"
                ],
                "answer": "27/01/1973"
            },
            {
                "question": "When did the countries of the world hold the conference to establish the United Nations?",
                "options": [
                    "World War II broke out",
                    "World War II had not yet taken place",
                    "World War II was about to end",
                    "In World War II"
                ],
                "answer": "World War II was about to end"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which army helped Vietnam in the war against France?",
                "options": [
                    "Chinese army",
                    "American army ",
                    "British army",
                    "Soviet army"
                ],
                "answer": "Chinese army"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which conference decided to divide Vietnam into two regions: North and South?",
                "options": [
                    "Geneva Conference 1954",
                    "Paris Conference 1973",
                    "Chengdu Conference 1990",
                    "Indochina Conference 1945"
                ],
                "answer": "Geneva Conference 1954"
            },
            {
                "question": "The three major financial economic centers of the world formed in the 70s of the 20th century were",
                "options": [
                    "America, England, France",
                    "America, Soviet Union, Japan",
                    "America, Japan, Western Europe",
                    "America, Germany, Japan"
                ],
                "answer": "America, Japan, Western Europe"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which attack led to the United States officially entering World War II?",
                "options": [
                    "The attack on Pearl Harbor",
                    "The attack on Normandy",
                    "The attack on Stalingrad",
                    "The attack on London"
                ],
                "answer": "The attack on Pearl Harbor"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which invention developed by Tim Berners-Lee in 1989 created the foundation of the World Wide Web?",
                "options": [
                    "Email",
                    "Web browser",
                    "HTML",
                    "Web search"
                ],
                "answer": "HTML"
            },
            {
                "question": "Who invented the airplane and made the first flight in 1903?",
                "options": [
                    "Charles Lindbergh",
                    "Amelia Earhart",
                    "The Wright Brothers",
                    "Igor Sikorsky"
                ],
                "answer": "The Wright Brothers"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which of the following countries did not follow the socialist path?",
                "options": [
                    "The Socialist Republic of Vietnam",
                    "Lao People's Democratic Republic.",
                    "People's Republic of China",
                    "Republic of Korea"
                ],
                "answer": "Republic of Korea"
            },
            {
                "question": "The construction of socialism since 1991 has continued to be maintained and promoted in which of the following countries?",
                "options": [
                    "China, Vietnam, Laos, Cuba",
                    "China, Russia, Vietnam, Laos",
                    "South Korea, North Korea, Vietnam, Cuba",
                    "Laos, Cuba, South Korea, Japan"
                ],
                "answer": "China, Vietnam, Laos, Cuba"
            },
            {
                "question": "Who invented the electric light bulb?",
                "options": [
                    "Alexander Graham Bell",
                    "Thomas Edison",
                    "Nikola Tesla",
                    "Michael Faraday"
                ],
                "answer": "Thomas Edison"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which achievement of the modern scientific and technological revolution has caused the world security situation to always have signs of instability?",
                "options": [
                    "Creating nuclear weapons",
                    "Discovering the human genome map",
                    "Creating spacecraft",
                    "Creating electronic computers"
                ],
                "answer": "Creating nuclear weapons"
            },
            {
                "question": "Who was the commander of the Japanese army during the attack on Pearl Harbor?",
                "options": [
                    "Isoroku Yamamoto",
                    "Franklin D. Roosevelt",
                    "Chiharu Shida",
                    "John F. Kennedy"
                ],
                "answer": "Isoroku Yamamoto"
            },
            {
                "question": "When did Vietnam join the United Nations? ",
                "options": [
                    "7-1976",
                    "7-1977",
                    "9-1977",
                    "7-1979"
                ],
                "answer": "9-1977"
            },
            {
                "question": "Who was the main leader of Germany during World War II?",
                "options": [
                    "Benito Mussolini",
                    "Adolf Hitler",
                    "Joseph Stalin",
                    "Franklin D. Roosevelt"
                ],
                "answer": "Adolf Hitler"
            },
            {
                "question": "Who was the president of the United States during World War II?",
                "options": [
                    "Woodrow Wilson",
                    "Theodore Roosevelt",
                    "Franklin D. Roosevelt",
                    "Warren G. Harding"
                ],
                "answer": "Franklin D. Roosevelt"
            }
        ],
        "hard": [
            {
                "question": "In which year did the Trung Sisters' uprising occur? ",
                "options": [
                    "179 BC",
                    "Year 40",
                    "Year 41",
                    "Year 39"
                ],
                "answer": "Year 40"
            },
            {
                "question": "In which year did Ngo Quyen ascend the throne? ",
                "options": [
                    "938",
                    "939",
                    "950",
                    "940"
                ],
                "answer": "939"
            },
            {
                "question": "To find a way to save the country, in 1905, Phan Boi Chau went to which country? ",
                "options": [
                    "China",
                    "Japan",
                    "Russia",
                    "Mexico"
                ],
                "answer": "Japan"
            },
            {
                "question": "Who was the first person to plant the flag on the roof of the Independence Palace on April 30, 1975? ?",
                "options": [
                    "Dang Toan",
                    "Bui Quang Than",
                    "Nguyen Van Tap",
                    "Hoang Dang Vinh"
                ],
                "answer": "Bui Quang Than"
            },
            {
                "question": "On September 2, 1945, in front of Ba Dinh Square, President Ho Chi Minh read the Declaration of Independence, giving birth to the country.............. ",
                "options": [
                    "The Socialist Republic of Vietnam",
                    "Vietnam",
                    "Democratic Republic of Vietnam",
                    "Republic of Vietnam"
                ],
                "answer": "Democratic Republic of Vietnam"
            },
            {
                "question": "The victory of which of the following campaigns ended the Vietnamese people's resistance war against the US to save the country (1954 - 1975)? ",
                "options": [
                    "Tay Nguyen Campaign",
                    "Hue-Da Nang Campaign",
                    "Ho Chi Minh Campaign",
                    "Tri-Thien Campaign"
                ],
                "answer": "Ho Chi Minh Campaign"
            },
            {
                "question": "When did the name 'Socialist Republic of Vietnam' come into being? ",
                "options": [
                    "September 2, 1945",
                    "July 2, 1976",
                    "February 12, 1951",
                    "July 2, 1975"
                ],
                "answer": "July 2, 1976"
            },
            {
                "question": "The United Nations operates according to the main principles: ",
                "options": [
                    "maintaining world peace and security",
                    "carrying out international cooperation between countries",
                    "developing friendly relations among nations ",
                    "the purpose of the Charter is clearly stated"
                ],
                "answer": "maintaining world peace and security"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which of the following organizations is not part of the United Nations? ",
                "options": [
                    "UNICEF",
                    "WTO",
                    "NATO",
                    "UNESCO"
                ],
                "answer": "NATO"
            },
            {
                "question": "In 1996, the US and Japanese governments met and decided to:   ",
                "options": [
                    "terminate the US-Japan Security Treaty",
                    "The US-Japan Security Treaty was extended for another 10 years",
                    "The US-Japan Security Treaty was extended for another 20 years",
                    "The US-Japan Security Treaty was extended permanently"
                ],
                "answer": "The US-Japan Security Treaty was extended permanently"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which Japanese cities were atomic bombs dropped on in August 1945? ",
                "options": [
                    "Tokyo and Nagoya",
                    "Hiroshima and Nagasaki",
                    "Kyoto and Yokohama",
                    "Osaka and Fukuoka"
                ],
                "answer": "Hiroshima and Nagasaki"
            },
            {
                "question": "Historically, the East Sea has been considered an essential route for transportation, trade, and migration between.......... ",
                "options": [
                    "Japan and Korea",
                    "China and India",
                    "Korea and China",
                    "India and Japan"
                ],
                "answer": "China and India"
            },
            {
                "question": "The invention of which of the following engines created the premise for the birth and development of cars and airplanes? ",
                "options": [
                    "Water engine",
                    "Internal combustion engine",
                    "Steam engine",
                    "Wind engine"
                ],
                "answer": "Internal combustion engine"
            },
            {
                "question": "In which country did the Industrial Revolution begin in the 18th century?",
                "options": [
                    "France",
                    "Japan",
                    "England",
                    "Australia"
                ],
                "answer": "England"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which army carried out the siege of Leningrad during World War II?",
                "options": [
                    "German Army",
                    "Italian Army",
                    "Japanese Army",
                    "French Army"
                ],
                "answer": "German Army"
            }
        ]
    },
    "fillInTheBlank": {
        "easy": [
            {
                "sentence": "The first king of the Tay Son dynasty was ___.",
                "answer": "Nguyen Hue"
              },
              {
                "sentence": "Which dynasty held the Dien Hong conference to mobilize the people to fight the enemy?",
                "answer": "Tran dynasty"
              },
              {
                "sentence": "Which dynasty was the last dynasty in Vietnamese feudal history?",
                "answer": "Nguyen"
              },
              {
                "sentence": "Where did Ly Thai To decide to move the capital from Hoa Lu in 1010?",
                "answer": "Ha Noi"
              },
              {
                "sentence": "In which year did President Ho Chi Minh read the declaration of independence?",
                "answer": "1945"
              },
              {
                "sentence": "Who invented the steam engine?",
                "answer": "James Watt"
              },
              {
                "sentence": "The inventor of the theory of universal gravitation was Isaac __________.",
                "answer": "Newton"
              },
              {
                "sentence": "The first industrial revolution began in __________.",
                "answer": "England"
              },
              {
                "sentence": "The first president of the United States was George __________.",
                "answer": "Washington"
              },
              {
                "sentence": "Which Polish scientist discovered the radioactive element radium?",
                "answer": "Marie Curie"
              },
              {
                "sentence": "Which Polish scientist discovered the radioactive element radium?",
                "answer": "Marie Curie"
              },
              {
                "sentence": "The United Nations was founded in __________",
                "answer": "1945"
              },
              {
                "sentence": "Christopher _________ was the discoverer of South America in 1492.",
                "answer": "Columbus"
              },
              {
                "sentence": "Which soccer player won the most Ballon d'Or awards?",
                "answer": "Messi"
              },
              {
                "sentence": "The inventor of the rabies vaccine was Louis __________",
                "answer": "Pasteur"
              },
              {
                "sentence": "Gravity was first explained by scientist Isaac ________.",
                "answer": "Newton"
              },
              {
                "sentence": "Ferdinand ______ was the first person to circumnavigate the Earth by sea.",
                "answer": "Magellan"
              }
        ],
        "normal": [
            {
                "sentence": "The year that Christopher Columbus discovered America was in",
                "answer": "1492"
              },
              {
                "sentence": "The Korean War lasted from ________ to 1953.",
                "answer": "1950"
              },
              {
                "sentence": "The industrial revolution first took place in England in the ________ century.",
                "answer": "18th"
              },
              {
                "sentence": "The Yalta Conference took place in ________ to discuss the reconstruction of Europe after World War II.",
                "answer": "1945"
              },
              {
                "sentence": "The great victory at Bach Dang in 938 helped Ngo Quyen gain independence from ________.",
                "answer": "China"
              },
              {
                "sentence": "General Vo Nguyen Giap is known as the great general of Vietnam in the ________ century.",
                "answer": "20th"
              },
              {
                "sentence": "In which year did the resistance war against France led by Ho Chi Minh and the Viet Minh end?",
                "answer": "1954"
              },
              {
                "sentence": "The signing of the Paris Peace Accords in 1972 ended the Vietnam War between Vietnam and ________.",
                "answer": "America"
              },
              {
                "sentence": "The Geneva Conference took place in ________ and decided to divide Vietnam into North and South.",
                "answer": "1954"
              },
              {
                "sentence": "World War I broke out in the year______.",
                "answer": "1914"
              },
              {
                "sentence": "The war against America started in ________ and ended in 1975.",
                "answer": "1954"
              },
              {
                "sentence": "Which year did World War II end with the surrender of Japan?",
                "answer": "1945"
              },
              {
                "sentence": "Germany was led by Adolf ______ during World War II.",
                "answer": "Hilter"
              },
              {
                "sentence": "The United Kingdom had the largest colonial system in history, sometimes referred to as 'the empire the sun never ______.'",
                "answer": "set"
              },
              {
                "sentence": "What year did Queen Elizabeth II pass away?",
                "answer": "2022"
              }
        ],
        "hard": [
            {
                "sentence": "The nationwide resistance war against France began on ________ December 1946.",
                "answer": "19"
              },
              {
                "sentence": "What year did the Tet Offensive take place?",
                "answer": "1968"
              },
              {
                "sentence": "What year did Vietnam join ASEAN?",
                "answer": "1995"
              },
              {
                "sentence": "Which year did US President Barack Obama officially visit Vietnam?",
                "answer": "2016"
              },
              {
                "sentence": "Which year did Vietnam first host the Southeast Asian Games (SEA Games)?",
                "answer": "2003"
              },
              {
                "sentence": "Vietnam successfully hosted the APEC Summit in Hanoi in ________.",
                "answer": "2006"
              },
              {
                "sentence": "How many times has Vietnam won the Southeast Asian Football Championship?",
                "answer": "2"
              },
              {
                "sentence": "Which year was the first time Vietnam won the Southeast Asian Football Championship?",
                "answer": "2008"
              },
              {
                "sentence": "In which year did the Paris Agreement on Vietnam stipulate that US troops must withdraw from Vietnam?",
                "answer": "1973"
              },
              {
                "sentence": "The Geneva Agreement stipulated the division of Vietnam at the ________ parallel after the resistance war against France.",
                "answer": "17"
              }
        ]
    }
}
